# Bonnie Mellott – UI/UX Developer

Knoxville, TN • 865-438-2636 • bonniemellott@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/bonniemellott/

#### Summary

Developer with creativity, excellent work ethic, and over a decade of professional experience creating engaging web applications. Both creative and logical, I bridge the gap between design and development. I'm looking for a rewarding position where I can stay on the cutting edge of web technology.

### Skills Tools

JavaScript, React/Redux, React Hooks, React Context API, Node.js, Styled Components, Sass, LESS, Expert at Cross-Browser Debugging Visual Studio Code, Webpack, Git, Sketch, Figma, Zeplin, Adobe Creative Suite

## Experience

9/2017-Present: Software Engineer - Level 3, Clayton Homes, Maryville, Tennessee

- Collaborate with devs/designers to create web apps using JavaScript, React/Redux, Node.js, and HTML5.
- Define and enforce style guides, coding standards, and best practices for client-side coding. Mentor other devs and act as a liaison between design and development.
- Led efforts to create a React component library using Storybook.js and Styled Components. This npm package and browsable storybook is currently being used across multiple teams.
- Continuously improve/refactor design, implementation, and performance of existing web applications.

7/2016-9/2017: Front End Engineer, Scripps Networks Interactive, Knoxville, Tennessee

- Worked with a distributed Agile team, as well as Product Design, to update and enhance web sites for HGTV, Food Network, Travel Channel, and other lifestyle brands.
- Refactored/improved frontend code sitewide. This included moving several brands to a single platform.
- Focused on optimizing performance of popular brand websites that receive millions of views per week.
- Integrated frontend code with a Java backend (Adobe CQ/Adobe Experience Manager)

9/2010-6/2016: Front End Web Developer, Clayton Homes, Maryville, Tennessee

- Worked in an Agile environment with a team of programmers and designers to develop and maintain hundreds of large-scale .net-driven websites for Retail Stores, Manufacturing Facilities, and Corporate.
- Mentored other developers and taught best practices about HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Led efforts to convert all Clayton home center sites, and the corporate site, to mobile-friendly responsive design.

  Completed the updates just before Google implemented their new mobile-friendly ranking algorithm. This resulted in higher search engine rankings, and a better user experience on mobile devices.
- Developed a parallax scrolling website about how Clayton Homes are built. This page was so engaging that users spent an average of nearly three minutes on it.

1/2005-9/2010: Web Designer, AT&T Internet Operations Group, Atlanta, Georgia

- Designed standards-compliant websites for YP.com customers using Photoshop, HTML and CSS.
- Fulfilled special requests and escalations for higher-profile advertisers.
- Responsible for continuous training/development of 20+ designers from one of AT&T's outside vendors.

3/2003-1/2005: Web Designer/Developer, Coolblue Interactive, Atlanta, Georgia

- Created visual design comps for web sites and web-based content management software
- Developed and tested database-driven web applications using PHP and MySQL.
- Guided clients in using Coolblue's Email Marketing Application

#### Education

7/2001-12/2004: The Art Institute of Atlanta, Atlanta, Georgia

Graduated with a Bachelor of Fine Arts degree in Interactive Media Design, GPA: 3.8

Won Best In Show at Graduation Portfolio Show, Had Perfect Attendance for 12 Consecutive Quarters